againstallgrain.com 2018-06-29

# Against All Grain Privacy Policy - Against All Grain | Against All Grain - Delectable paleo recipes to eat & feel great

**Date Last Revised: August 16, 2013**

### Overview

Your privacy is of great concern to me. I work extremely hard at all times to maintain your anonymity and prevent unauthorized access to your data. I’ve developed this Privacy Policy to explain how my site collects, uses and discloses your information. Please take a moment to review this policy and do not hesitate to contact me with any questions at: legal@againstallgrain.com.

### Collection and Use of Personal and Anonymous Information

Personal information is defined as data that can be used to identify you, and possibly contact you. I maintain strict standards when I work with personal information.

Anonymous information is information that cannot be used to identify you.

I will collect and use your information in the following ways:

#### 1\. When you browse the Against All Grain Website

I use several tools to see how you interact with the Against All Grain website. I use this data to improve my site so that you are able to find more relevant information faster. The way that I track your visits is through Google Analytics. Google Analytics uses your IP address to see what pages you browse, for how long and what website you were browsing before you came to the site.

#### 2\. When you fill out a web form to Subscribe to my Mailing List

When browsing my website, you may fill-out my MailChimp web form that may ask for your name, address, phone number, and email address. The information you enter into is used to contact you to share recent blog posts, and keep you informed on any updates to my website. At any time, you are able to ask me to delete your data, or you may unsubscribe using the link at the bottom of any email sent to you.

#### I will always treat your info with the highest regard

In all cases, I adhere to the strictest of policies regarding the use of personal information once collected. I directly do not disclose this information to any third-parties, except those listed below.

### Disclosure to Third Parties

I may employ third party companies to facilitate providing you valuable services. For example, I use a cloud based email marketing management tool called MailChimp to better connect with you as my reader. In all instances I make sure that your data is transferred over a secure transmission link and that the third parties I use have the highest quality security standards in place. Today, I use two main cloud service providers to best serve you as the customer. I’ve included their website addresses and links to their security policies below for your ease of reference:

**Dropbox** – [Website](https://dropbox.com/ "Dropbox Website") – [Security Policy](https://www.dropbox.com/privacy#security "Dropbox Security Policy")

**MailChimp** – [Website](https://mailchimp.com/ "MailChimp Website") – [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/ "MailChimp Privacy Policy")

### Advertising

I can only provide so much content to you for free without going bankrupt or having my husband pull the plug. To that end, I’ve put advertisements on the right side-bar of my site. These ads are served by the Google Adsense platform. As I am sure you are aware, these ads can be directly tied to search terms you put in to Google. As such, these ads also track items that I am not in control over. However, should you see ads that are offensive, or crude, please notify my immediately at: legal@againstallgrain.com so I can remove them from my Adsense account.

To learn more about tracking I suggest you visit: http://donttrack.us/

In addition, I use the WP-DoNotTrack plugin to comply with people who wish not to be tracked while on the website.  Should you not wish to be tracked, please select the Do Not Track option from your internet browser.

### Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a person’s computer for record-keeping purposes. I will notify you if I am using cookies to track your usage in accordance with EU Law.  Should you not wish for me to use cookies, the most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser. I suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at [the About Cookies website](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) which offers guidance for all modern browsers.

So you know why you should opt-in, I use cookies to track website visitors and improve the site. For example, through the use of cookies, I may find that visitors are viewing one of my blog posts for an average time of only 10 seconds. With that knowledge, I would write more engaging blog posts, resulting in a website that is enjoyable and informational for you! If you reject cookies, you may still use my site, but your experience may not be as optimal and I will be less informed on how to improve my ability to serve you.

### California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 and Business and Professions Code Section 22575 permits visitors who are California residents to request that I not share their personal information with third parties for such direct marketing purposes. If you would still like to make such a request, send an email with “California Privacy” in the subject line to the email address specified in “Contact Information,” below.

### Notification of Privacy Statement Changes

I may update the Privacy Policy to reflect changes to my information practices. If I make any material changes I will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified when you signed up with MailChimp) or by means of a notice on my website prior to the change becoming effective. I encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### Contact Information

If you have any questions or comments about the Privacy Policy, please contact: legal@againstallgrain.com
